carryology.com 2019-04-13

# Privacy Policy - Carryology - Exploring better ways to carry

**Privacy Policy**

_Effective Date: 25 May 2018_

**Introduction**

Carryology takes privacy seriously – we are committed to keeping your personal information private.  All personal data we collect is kept strictly secured, and is only used for the purposes described in this privacy policy.

This privacy policy applies to information collected through our websites and any information we collect offline (for example, if you talk to our customer services team).

**Who are ‘we’?**

When we talk about “we” (or “our” or “us”), we mean Carryology Pty Ltd and all its wholly owned subsidiaries.  We are based in Australia but we review gear from all over the world.

For European Union data protection purposes, when we act as a controller in relation to your personal data, Samuel Giles is our representative in the European Union.  You can contact him on [eu-privacy@carryology.co.uk](mailto:eu-privacy@bellroy.co.uk).

**What is ‘personal data’**

Personal data is any data that could directly or indirectly identify you – this includes information like your name, address, telephone number and your email address but in some cases it may include less obviously identifying information, like your IP Address (see below).

**What data do we collect**

When you visit carryology.com or sign up for a newsletter or other publication, we collect information about you and your use of our website.  We treat this information as falling into three categories: Customer Information, Usage Data and your IP Address.

**Customer Information** is the information you explicitly provide to us when you make sign up to receive our publications, including your:

  * -Name
  * -Email address

**Usage Data** is general information about how you interact with our website, such as:

  * -which pages you visited on our website
  * -how you came to the website (for example, by clicking on a link in a newsletter or from an advertisement)
  * -which buttons or links you clicked
  * -whether you have been to the website before

Whenever you visit a website (including ours), the computer from which the web pages are served (i.e. our web server) needs to know your computer’s public network address so it can send the requested pages to your browser.  The public network address associated with your computer is called its “public **IP Address** ” and is sent automatically each time you access any Internet website.  From a computer’s IP Address, it is usually possible to determine the general geographic location of that computer but often not the specific computer and if multiple people use the computer not the specific user (although if your IP Address is unique to you and is published somewhere or if you later identify yourself while while using the same IP Address, it is possible that IP Address could identify you).

In the European Union, your IP Address is considered to be personal data, and we treat it accordingly.

**How we collect data**

Information you provide to us directly: We may ask you to provide personal data when you sign up for a newsletter, respond to an offer, join us on social media, take part in surveys or contact us for help.  If you don’t want to provide personal data, you don’t have to, but it might limit your ability to do certain things on the website.

Information we collect automatically: When you visit carryology.com, we collect some information about you automatically, including Usage Data.

Some of this information is collected using cookies or other similar tracking technologies that have been placed by us or by third parties.  For details of how cookies work, which ones we use and how you can control them, please see our cookie policy below. 

**How we use data**

Where we collect your personal data, we’ll only process it:

  * where we have legitimate interests to process the personal data and our interests are not overridden by your rights, or
  * in accordance with a legal obligation, or
  * where we have your explicit consent.

The main reason we use your personal data is to manage our relationship with you.

We also use personal data for other purposes, including:

To communicate with you: this may include providing you with information you’ve requested or that we’re required to provide to you, that relates to changes to our website or policies, marketing communications in accordance with your preferences or to invite you to provide feedback or to take part in research we are conducting.

To support you: this may include dealing with any questions you have about products, or any issues relating to goods or services.

To improve our website: we use Usage Data to help us understand the online behaviour of our visitors, which helps us to focus our marketing activities and improve the services we provide on the website.  Using web analytics on our website enables us to measure, collect, analyse and report on Usage Data for the purposes of understanding and optimising visitors’ experiences on our website.  We try to ensure that all Usage Data is anonymised (i.e. not referable to a specific person) unless we have your consent.

Geographical location information contained in Usage Data also enables us to tailor your experience on our website by displaying different content based on your location, such as providing content in your preferred language (where possible), showing local currency and pricing, and showing relevant advertising.  Again, geographical location information is anonymised unless we have your consent.

To market to you: we use Usage Data for remarketing (sometimes called retargeting) to better target our ads and those of our affiliates.  Retargeting uses cookies to identify visitors who visit a certain website and then doing something with that information, such as showing a particular brand of goods or services on other websites.  So, after you have visited our website, you (or another user of your computer) may see related ads on certain participating third party websites, such as on the Google Display Network and Facebook. This will only occur if you have agreed to us using non-essential cookies.

To analyse, aggregate and report: we may use the personal data we collect about you and other users of our website to produce aggregated and anonymised analytics and reports, which we may share with third parties.

**How we can share your personal data (and how we don’t)**

There will be times when we need to share your personal data with third parties.  We will only disclose your personal data to:

  * distribute direct marketing materials that you have consented to receive (MailChimp)
  * connect to social networks (for example, Pinterest, Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn)
  * pay commission to affiliates
  * target advertising (for example, Google, Facebook)

There also may be times when we are legally required to disclose personal data, such as to regulators, law enforcement bodies, government agencies, courts or other third parties where we think it’s necessary to comply with applicable laws and regulations, or to exercise our legal rights.  Where possible and appropriate, we will notify you of this kind of disclosure.

We only share your Customer Information with third parties where you have consented to receive direct marketing material (such as MailChimp).

Your personal data is never disclosed to third parties for remarketing or retargeting purposes.  Carryology never sells its email lists or customer information.

**International data transfers**

When we collect, process and share data in accordance with this privacy policy, it may be transferred to countries other than where you live.  Our data hosting provider’s servers are located in the United States, and many of the third parties with whom we share data are also located in the United States.

When we do transfer data, we will make sure that there are safeguards in place to protect your personal data.

For individuals in the European Union (EU), this means that your personal data will be transferred outside of the EU.  EU personal data will only be transferred to countries that have been identified as providing adequate protection for EU data (such as New Zealand) or to a third party where we have approved transfer mechanisms in place – this means that we have either entered into an appropriate Data Processing Agreement or by ensuring that the entity has appropriate data protection in place, including where the entity is [Privacy Shield](http://www.privacyshield.com/welcome) certified (for US-based third parties).

For any information stored in Australia, we use appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect the personal data that we collect and process. The measures we use are designed to provide a level of security appropriate to the risk of processing your personal data.  Carryology also complies with the [Australian Privacy Principles](https://www.oaic.gov.au/privacy-law/privac%20y-act/australian-privacy-principles) in relation to the proper use and storage of personal data.

**Retention**

How long we retain your personal data depends on what it is, what we need it for and whether we are legally required to keep it.  Once we no longer need to retain it, we will make sure your personal data is deleted or anonymised.

**Your rights**

Your personal data belongs to you, and you have the right to:

  * know what personal data we hold about you
  * make sure that all personal data is correct and up-to-date
  * ask us to correct any personal data
  * object to our continued processing of your personal data

If you no longer wish to receive any online communications, just let us know by clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of the newsletter or other communication.

You can notify us if you no longer wish us to process your personal data, but we not that if you do so, this may mean that we can no longer provide our services to you.

You can contact us at any time by emailing [privacy@carryology.com](mailto:privacy@bellroy.com) or, if you are in the EU, email [eu-privacy@carryology.co.uk](mailto:eu-privacy@bellroy.co.uk) and we will respond to your request within one month.

If you have any complaints or concerns about how we manage your personal data, please contact us by emailing [privacy@carryology.com](mailto:privacy@bellroy.com).  If you are in the European Union, you also have the right to complain to your local [Data Protection Authority](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/reform/what-are-data-protection-authorities-dpas_en) about the collection and use of your Personal Data.

For details of how to manage cookies, see our cookie policy below. 

**Changes to this Policy**

We may revise this privacy policy from time to time as we add new features or as laws change. When we make changes to our privacy policy, they are reflected on this page and the a revision date will be noted at the top. Any revised privacy policy will apply to personal data, Customer Information and Usage Data we already have about you at the time of the change, and any such information created or received after the change takes effect. We strongly recommend that you periodically reread this privacy policy to see if there have been any changes that may affect you.

**How to contact us**

You can contact us by emailing [privacy@carryology.com](mailto:privacy@bellroy.com) or, if you are in the EU, [eu-privacy@carryology.](mailto:eu-privacy@bellroy.com)co.uk.

Carryology Pty Ltd

5 Theatre Place

Canterbury

Victoria 3126

Australia

**Cookie Policy**

Last revised: 25 May 2018

**What is a cookie?**

A cookie is a small text file that is set in your browser when you visit a website, and which may assign an anonymous identifier to you.

**What cookies/tracking technologies do we use?**

There are a few different types of cookies that we and some of our affiliates and third-party service providers may use: persistent cookies (that stay on your hard drive until removed) and session ID cookies (that automatically expire after a period of time, or when you close your browser).

There are also other tracking technologies that may be used, such as web beacons and local storage.  Web beacons allow us to monitor site behaviour by delivering your IP address, any cookies we may have set and information about the page you’re visiting to a server.  We use local storage to keep track of your preferences, things you’ve seen, temporary personal identifiers and more; the data we store in local storage generally stays on your device.

**Why do we use cookies/tracking technologies?**

We use cookies (and other tracking technologies – but for ease, let’s just call them cookies) for lots of reasons: they let us customise your experience (for example, seeing prices in the correct currency), operate the website and generally make sure that your experience of our website is a good one.  We also use cookies to perform analytics and deliver advertising or marketing that is relevant to you.

There are also cookies set by third parties that allow us to provide interactive content, perform analytics and enable other third party features, like payment or links to social media.

**How can you control cookies?**

You can control cookies by amending your web browser controls.  You can also delete existing cookies from your web browser and/or disabling cookies on your computer and other devices.  Depending on the particular browser you are using (for example, Google Chrome, Safari, Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox), this can usually be done by accessing the ‘Browsing History’ through the ‘Settings’ or ‘Options’ menu (or equivalent) in your web browser, or if you are using a different device, then in the ‘Settings’ for that device.

Some cookies are essential to the proper operation of our website: if you disable cookies in your web browser, or delete existing cookies, our website may not work properly and your experience with our website will be less personalised and may make your shopping experience less enjoyable.

It is important to remember that if you delete existing cookies but do not disable cookies in your web browser, and then you subsequently visit our (or any) website, fresh cookies may be placed and you may need to repeat the process of deleting existing cookies.

You can also opt out of targeted advertising: see [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) or [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

You can also alter your ad preference settings on Google, Facebook and other third parties, and on the platforms of other providers.

Finally, if you do opt out of receiving communications directly from us, we will no longer use your information for those purposes.

**Do Not Track**

Some browsers allow you to automatically notify websites that you visit not to track you by using a ‘Do Not Track’ signal.  If you have Do Not Track enabled when you visit our website, we will treat that as you having rejected cookies and not place any cookies other than those essential to the proper functioning of our website.
